<changelog>

    <release versionCode="42" versionName="v1.5.2" date="2022-02-06">
        <new name="summary">Revamped user interface</new>
        <new name="summary">Added UI visibility toggle</new>
        <new name="summary">Added (Settings) -> (Advanced) -> (Ultra High Resolutions)</new>
    </release>

    <release versionCode="40" versionName="v1.5.1" date="2021-11-01">
        <new name="summary">5 new bookmarks!</new>
        <new name="summary">2 new palettes!</new>
        <new name="summary">Logarithmic functions added to the custom shape creator!</new>
        <new name="summary">'Randomize' feature added to the options menu!</new>
        <new name="summary">Many bug fixes and improved crash reporting system!</new>
    </release>


    <release versionCode="37" versionName="v1.5.0" date="2021-07-15">
        <info>Improved user interface - smaller, new adjust buttons, and more!</info>
        <info>Added tutorial! Accessible by going to (Settings) -> (Tutorial)</info>
        <info>GOLD: Make copies of palettes and shapes! (Long click an item and press the copy button)</info>
        <info>GOLD: Added inverse trigonometry functions to the custom shape creator!</info>
        <info>Added (Settings) -> (Unrestricted Parameters)</info>
        <info>Added 2 new palettes: Eye, Who</info>
    </release>


    <release versionCode="33" versionName="v1.4.4" date="2021-03-25">
        <info>Bookmark your fractals! -- Access bookmarks through (Image) -> (Bookmarks)</info>
        <info>Added 28 default bookmarks</info>
        <info>Param 1 of the Kleinian shape can now create spirals</info>
        <info>Added 2 new textures: Image 1 and Image 2</info>
        <info>Added 1 new shape: Angelbrot</info>
        <info>Added Seed parameter to most shapes</info>
        <info>Added (Color) -> (Accent)</info>
        <info>Zooming past 1e-6 on shapes like Sine 1 is now disabled by default... Go to (Settings) -> (Allow Slow Renders) to enable</info>
    </release>


    <release versionCode="32" versionName="v1.4.3" date="2021-01-20">
        <info>Added 5 new textures: Converge Time (Smooth), Disc Lens, Star Lens, Sine Lens, Field Lines</info>
        <info>Added 2 new color palettes: Fusion, Refraction</info>
        <info>Fixed custom shape calculator bug</info>
    </release>


    <release versionCode="30" versionName="v1.4.1" date="2021-01-10">
        <info>Added (Image) -> (Ratio) for saving images of different sizes</info>
        <info>Double-tap in (Position) mode to increase zoom</info>
        <info>Added (Settings) -> (Use Alternate Split Method) to fix zooming on certain devices</info>
        <info>Moved settings menu</info>
        <info>Fixed dual-precision bug on certain devices</info>
        <info>Fixed display bug when changing position</info>
        <info>Fixed memory usage crash when showing GOLD upgrade screen</info>
        <info>Fixed crash when creating palettes with more than 8 colors</info>
        <info>Fixed bugs with multiple textures on certain devices</info>
    </release>


    <release versionCode="27" versionName="v1.4.0" date="2020-12-12">
        <info>Added Gold upgrade!</info>
        <info>Added several new shapes, textures, color palettes, and parameters</info>
        <info>GOLD: Added custom shape and custom color palette creation</info>
        <info>GOLD: Added higher resolution options up to 4K</info>
        <info>Added ability to choose favorites in item lists</info>
        <info>Added RATE option to all parameters for more controlled adjustments</info>
        <info>Resolution automatically chosen during parameter changes</info>
        <info>Improved memory usage</info>
    </release>


    <release versionCode="18" versionName="v1.3.4" date="2020-07-22">
        <info>All shapes now support deep zoom (up to 1e-12) with textures</info>
        <info>Escape Time (Smooth) texture now compatible with all divergent shapes</info>
        <info>Stripe Average and Curvature Average textures improved (no discontinuities)</info>
        <info>Color palettes Time, Starling, Overgrown, and Pagoda added</info>
        <info>Increase SETTINGS -> RENDER -> CHUNKS if the app crashes for high values of SHAPE -> ITERATE</info>
        <info>Fixed TEXTURE -> MODE -> IN/BOTH settings</info>
        <info>Fixed COLOR -> AUTO errors</info>
        <info>Fixed another bug that caused crash on startup</info>
    </release>


    <release versionCode="17" versionName="v1.3.3" date="2020-06-25">
        <info>Added support for devices with OpenGL ES 3.0/3.1</info>
        <info>Fixed several bugs that caused crash on startup</info>
    </release>


    <release versionCode="16" versionName="v1.3.2" date="2020-06-15">
        <info>Color palettes Chroma, Island, Rose, Kingfisher, Bioluminescent, Atlas, Fossil, Alpha, Peach, Jazz, and Polygon added</info>
        <info>Interrupt image render process by changing position/resolution</info>
        <info>Toggle COLOR -> AUTO to automatically fit colors based on position</info>
        <info>Deeper zoom (without textures, up to 1e-12) available on transcendental shapes i.e. Mandelbrot (Power), Clover, Sine 1, Sine 2, Horseshoe Crab, and Kleinian</info>
        <info>More resolution options</info>
        <info>Larger menu height when changing texture/shape/palette</info>
        <info>Enabling SETTINGS -> CONTINUOUS RENDER disables SETTINGS -> RENDER BACKGROUND</info>
        <info>Hints added for SHAPE -> ITERATE</info>
    </release>


</changelog>